{
  "reference_number": "11120",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "The Science is clear that we need to hit net zero carbon emissions by 2050. Be ambitious and commit to this. Then make it happen."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Carbon dioxide is not the most powerful greenhouse gas. We need to address this issue holistically."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": "If carbon credits were issued to farmers for building top soil this would be a more stable way to store carbon than forestry which will\n\n be harvested. It would also address the issue of soil erosion and the fast pace loss of fertility currently happening in New Zealand. It\n would be easy to measure and incentivise good farming practice, conserving soil and improving water quality due to reduced runoff."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "New information is always coming to light. It is important to be able to respond to that."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - the third emissions budget should be able to be changed but only when the subsequent budget is set",
      "answer_index": 4,
      "notes": "Responding to changes is important however I fear that a government less concerned with environmental issues could simply\n\n undermine the process and commitments if they can just change the budgets."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It is important to remember that an economy can only exist in an environment that is able to support a human society that creates\n\nthe economy. There is no trade off between economy and environment. We have to choose to make our environment a priority or we\nwon't have an economy to worry about. I don't understand what the consideration of \"social circumstances and, in particular, the likely\n\nimpact of the decision on fuel poverty\" means. is it just a miss spelling? I think it is important to consider the impacts on society and\nmake sure decisions are made that don't make increase poverty but rather lift those in poverty out and give them opportunities to\nwork in a clean energy future."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "How to incentivise emission reductions across all sectors. How to support the transition to a clean energy future to avoid social and\neconomic chaos. Talk to banks about their lending and mandate that they divest from fossil fuel and poor agricultural practice. Look at\nthe oceans as an important global carbon sink and set aside large areas of marine park to ensure the resilience of the oceanic\n\necosystems."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "I don't think they should have decision making power but it is important they can hold the government to account."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I think all listed are good but considering NZ large agricultural emissions I think the Climate Change Commissioners need to\n\nunderstand farming and how to transition farms to a zero emissions model."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We are already experiencing impacts of climate change. We will have to adapt. So building this into the plan is essential."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Couldn't see what these functions would be."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Be bold.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
